Okay, let's see
what we got here.
好吧，让我们看看这里有什么。
Seen it. Seen it.
看过了。看过了。
Huh. What's this about?
嗯。这是怎么回事？
At the dawn...
dawn... dawn...
在黎明……黎明……黎明…
dawn... dawn... dawn...
黎明……黎明……黎明…
Ah. Here we go.
啊。开始吧。
At the dawn of time,
在时间的黎明，
there was our gracious
and powerful creator,
那里有我们仁慈而强大的造物主，
Primus.
博智。
To protect our universe,
he sacrificed his life force,
为了保护我们的宇宙，他牺牲了自己的生命力，
transforming himself
into our planet,
将自己变成我们的星球，
Cybertron.
塞伯坦。
From within Cybertron's core,
来自塞伯坦的核心，
Primus birthed
the first Transformers
Primus诞生了第一个变形金刚
known as the Primes,
被称为质数，
the most powerful
Transformers,
最强大的变形金刚，
appointed to lead and protect
future generations.
被任命为领导和保护子孙后代。
To assist them, Primus created
an entity of great power,
为了帮助他们，Primus创造了一个强大的实体，
the Matrix of Leadership.
领导矩阵。
The Matrix, there it is. Okay.
Good. Come on. Keep going.
黑客帝国，在那里。好吧。好。来吧。继续。
With the Matrix
in the Primes' possession,
当矩阵为质数所有时，
Cybertron's natural
power source, Energon,
flowed in abundance,
塞伯坦的天然能量源，能量，大量流动，
sustaining life
across the planet.
维持地球上的生命。
Attention!
Unauthorized movement
detected in archival vault.
注意!在档案库中检测到未经授权的移动。
Sector J-3.
部门J-3。
KDQ-12 to KDK-1.
KDQ-12到KDK-1。
Breaching archives
in ten seconds.
在十秒内破坏档案。
For generations,
there was peace and prosperity,
世代和平繁荣，
until the Matrix
of Leadership was lost,
直到领导力矩阵丢失，
causing Energon
to no longer flow.
导致能量不再流动。
Why does every legend
about the Matrix
end right there?
为什么所有关于黑客帝国的传说都到此结束？
One of these
has to say what happened.
其中必须有一个能说明发生了什么。
Halt, criminal!
Prepare to be detained!
停止,犯罪!准备被扣留吧！
Oh, hey there.
Halt, criminal!
Prepare to--
哦，大家好。停止,犯罪!准备——
Uh-oh.
哦。
Freeze!
Get down!
冻结!下来!
Well, hello, guys.
I'm so glad you're here.
大家好。我很高兴你能来。
Which way is the exit?
出口在哪个方向？
I must've taken a wrong turn.
我一定是拐错弯了。
It's that defective mining bot,
Oreon Pix!
是那个有缺陷的采矿机器人，Oreon Pix！
Orion Pax.
Who cares?
猎户座Pax。谁在乎呢?
We told you
to never come back here!
我们告诉过你别再来这里！
Why are we all yelling?
I'm gonna smash you!
我们为什么都大喊大叫？我要打烂你！
Hold on.
Whoa, whoa, hold on.
No need for violence.
等一等。等等，等等。不需要暴力。
How about this:
I run away, you chase me.
We play that game. Huh?
这样怎么样：我逃跑，你追我。我们玩这个游戏。嗯?
Come on.
You're bigger, faster.
It'll be fun.
来吧。你更大，更快。会很有趣的。
He doesn't have a cog.
Let's give him a head start.
他没有齿轮。让我们给他一个先机。
Why not?
It's not like
he can transform.
为什么不呢?他又不会变形。
Oh, yeah?
噢,是吗?
Well, watch this.
好吧，看看这个。
Get him!
得到他!
I-- I-- Uh...
我——我——呃……
Something that flies.
会飞的东西。会飞的东西。
Prepare to be detained!
准备被扣留！
Halt, criminal!
Prepare to be detained!
停止,犯罪!准备被扣留吧！
Halt, criminal!
停止,犯罪!
Come on! Start! Come on!
来吧!开始了!来吧!
Whoa!
哇!
Whoa. No, no, no, no!
哇。不，不，不，不！
There he is!
他来了！
Ha-ha! So long, suck--
哈哈!再见了，混蛋
Ooh, Energon.
哦,Energon。
Evening, everyone.
Pardon me.
晚上,每一个人。原谅我。
Hey!
嘿!
Whoa!
哇!
Ah, it's Orion.
Seriously, again?
啊，是猎户座。说真的,一遍吗?
Okay, fellas!
Thanks for the head start.
好吧,伙计们!谢谢你的抢先一步。
You want to give me
another one?
你想再给我一个吗？
You're dead!
I'll take that as a no.
你死了!我就当你不同意了。
Hey!
Watch where you're going!
嘿!看路！
Oh...
What did you say, no-cog?
哦……你说什么，无齿轮？
Sorry, sir,
I didn't mean you.
对不起，先生，我不是说你。
I was referring
to the bot
who was behind you.
我指的是在你后面的那个机器人。
What? Where'd he go?
怎么啦？他去哪儿了？
The filthy
red and blue bot?
那个肮脏的红蓝相间的机器人？
Has a big mouth,
squeaky joints,
嘴巴很大，关节吱吱作响，
gives off a corroded
metallic stench?
散发出金属腐蚀的恶臭？
Where is he?
He went that way.
他在哪里？他朝那边走去。
When I get
my hands on that bot...
等我拿到那个机器人…
All right, all clear.
好了，没事了。
Okay, D-16,
I may be a little rusty,
好吧，D-16，我可能有点生疏了，
but "corroded"?
That is too far.
但“腐蚀”?太远了。
Let me guess.
Chased out of
the archives?
让我猜猜。被赶出档案馆？
Yeah.
I had to jump
out of a window this time.
是的。这次我只能从窗户跳下去了。
Almost died.
It was wild.
几乎死亡。太疯狂了。
And digging through
ancient data
is worth dying for?
挖掘古代数据值得为之付出生命吗？
Yes, it is.
是的，它是。
I need a new best friend.
我需要一个新的好朋友。
If there are clues
in our recorded history
如果我们的历史记录中有线索
that can help locate
the Matrix of Leadership,
可以帮助找到领导力矩阵，
they're in the archives.
它们在档案馆里。
Sentinel Prime,
the Sentinel Prime,
擎天柱，擎天柱
is up on the surface
right now,
现在就在海面上，
risking his life for us
in search of the Matrix.
冒着生命危险寻找母体。
That's exactly what I'm doing.
I'm trying to help him.
这正是我正在做的。我是想帮他。
Yeah, okay.
是的,好的。
The sooner Energon
flows again,
能量流得越快，
the sooner we won't
have to mine for it.
我们就不用挖矿了。
Don't you want
to choose your own path,
do whatever you want?
难道你不想选择自己的道路，做你想做的事吗？
We're miners.
We mine, that's all.
我们的矿工。我们是我的，仅此而已。
No, there has got to be
something more I can do.
I can feel it.
不，我肯定还能做些什么。我能感觉到。
Oh, yeah? Like the time
you had a "feeling"
噢,是吗?就像你有一种“感觉”
you could transform
without a cog?
没有齿轮你也能变形？
You said you were never
gonna mention that again.
你说过你不会再提那件事的。
Took me three days
to pry you open.
我花了三天才把你撬开。
Your feelings
get you in trouble.
你的感觉会给你带来麻烦。
Yeah, yeah.
是的,是的。
Just trust
in Sentinel Prime.
I do trust in him.
只要相信哨兵擎天柱。我确实信任他。
Hey, if we did have cogs--
如果我们真有齿轮的话
I'd transform
into a shovel
and beat you.
我会变成铁锹揍你。
I don't like how fast
you answered that.
我不喜欢你回答得这么快。
But listen, if you did beat me,
I couldn't give you this awesome
但听着，如果你真的赢了我，我不会给你这么棒的
Megatronus Prime thing
I have here. It's cool.
我这里有威震天王。天气凉爽。
I'll give it
to someone else.
What Megatronus Prime thing?
我把它给别人。什么威震天王的东西？
Ah, it's nothing.
Just a, you know,
啊，没什么。只是，你知道，
mint-condition Megatronus Prime
decal, first edition.
全新威震天王贴花，第一版。
What?
怎么啦？
If you don't want it,
I can just throw it away.
如果你不想要，我可以把它扔掉。
Throw it away? Don't--
That's not funny.
Let me see.
扔掉？别——这一点都不好笑。让我看看。
Wait. Don't grab.
You're gonna crease it.
等待。不要抓住。你要把它弄皱。
You know, Sentinel says
Megatronus was the--
哨兵说威震天是
The strongest Prime
to ever live.
有史以来最强大的擎天柱。
I know, buddy.
我知道，伙计。
Looks good on you.
Ah, it's really cool.
你穿起来很好看。啊，真的很酷。
Thanks.
Always got your back.
谢谢。永远支持你。
No matter what.
无论如何。
Approaching sublevel station.
Stand clear of doors.
接近分段站。请远离门。
Mining teams,
prepare to unload.
采矿队，准备卸货。
Metal to the pedal, drill bits.
This is it.
金属到踏板，钻头。就是这里。
How much Energon have you mined
under my leadership?
在我的领导下，你们开采了多少能量？
So much, Elita-1!
够了，Elita-1！
And how perfect
is my mining record?
我的采矿记录有多完美？
So perfect, Elita-1!
太完美了，Elita-1！
We are a mere
30 units of Energon away
我们只差30单位能量了
from my promotion to supervisor.
从我升职为主管开始。
Are you happy for me?
你为我高兴吗？
So happy, Elita-1!
太高兴了，Elita-1！
Elita-- I mean Captain,
埃莉塔，我是说船长，
you are looking especially shiny
this morning. New polish?
你今天早上看起来特别有光泽。新波兰吗?
Orion Pax,
I'm sorry that I somehow
猎户座帕克斯，很抱歉我不知怎么
gave you the impression
that we're friends.
让你以为我们是朋友。
Apology accepted.
接受道歉。
Light up that wall!
Let's go! Ten seconds!
把那面墙点亮！我们走吧!十秒!
Happy to take
the lead today, Captain.
很高兴今天能带队，上尉。
Feeling like I have
enough power in me
感觉自己有足够的力量
to drill down
and touch Primus myself.
亲自去接触普里默斯
You don't have
the touch or the power.
你没有那种触觉和能力。
Ready positions,
rust buckets! Let's go!
各就各位，铁锈桶！我们走吧!
She's in a good mood today.
Mm-hmm.
她今天心情很好。嗯哼。
You ready?
Always ready.
你准备好了吗?总是准备好了。
Let's punch in.
我们打卡吧。
Here we go.
This one won't be open long.
开始吧。这家店开不了多久。
Brace it up!
振作起来！
Here we go! Bridge!
我们开始吧！桥!
Brace up!
振作起来!
Lower channel is open.
下通道打开。
Drill power on max!
开足马力！
Low bridge!
桥低!
Drill it out!
把它钻出来！
I tapped a vein!
我敲了一下静脉！
It's unstable!
We got to go, we got to move!
不稳定!我们得走了，快走！
Evacuate!
撤离!
Everyone out!
Evacuate immediately!
每个人都出去!立即撤离!
The tunnel is closing.
隧道正在关闭。
I repeat, the tunnel is closing!
重复，隧道要关闭了！
You with me, D?
On your six! Keep going!
你跟得上我吗，D？六点钟方向！继续前进!
Look out!
当心!
Jazz is stuck!
爵士被困住了！
Elita, we've got
a trapped miner.
艾丽塔，有个矿工被困了。
I'm falling back to assist.
我后退去协助。
Negative.
Do not break protocol.
Evacuate!
负的。不要破坏协议。撤离!
We're gonna need more lift.
我们需要更多的力。
It's closing!
Just grab your pack and go.
关闭!拿上你的背包就走。
Yeah. Good idea.
是的。好主意。
What? No, I didn't mean it!
怎么啦？不，我不是那个意思！
Pull him clear!
把他拉出来！
Pax, what's happening?
帕克斯，发生什么事了？
Nothing much. Just normal
protocol-following stuff.
没有什么要紧的事。只是正常的协议遵循的东西。
It's all good.
一切都很好。
Oh, that's not good.
哦，那可不太好。
Orion Pax, could you please exit
the tunnel of death?
猎户座·帕克斯，你能离开死亡隧道吗？
Elita, it's about
to get messy out there!
Elita，外面要乱起来了！
Go, go, go!
快，快，快！
Run! Run!
快跑!快跑!
Hurry!
We're not gonna make it!
快点!我们赶不上了！
Come on! Go, go, go!
来吧!快，快，快！
What the hell, Pax?
I told you to evacuate.
搞什么鬼，帕克斯？我告诉过你撤离。
I did, eventually.
If I get fired because of you--
我最终做到了。如果我因为你被炒了
Oh, please.
They're not
gonna fire you.
哦,请。他们不会解雇你的。
Elita-1, you're fired.
艾丽塔一号，你被解雇了。
What? Why? I followed
protocol to the letter.
怎么啦？为什么?我严格遵守了礼仪。
That is true.
I was the one
who broke the rules.
这是真的。是我打破了规则。
No one asked you!
没人问你！
Darkwing, please,
I've worked too hard
for this.
暗翼，求你了，为了这个我太努力了。
You are no-cog bots
with limited options.
你们是没有齿轮的机器人，选择有限。
Report to waste management
immediately.
立即向废物管理部门报告。
Waste management?
废物管理?
Elita...
Next time,
why don't you stop and think
Elita……下次，你为什么不停下来想想
before you ruin someone's life?
在你毁了别人的生活之前？
I'm sorry!
我很抱歉!
Hey, Darkwing!
Don't do it.
嘿,Darkwing !不要这样做。
I may not have a cog,
but my finger can transform.
我也许没有齿轮，但我的手指可以变形。
Guess which one?
I'll give you
a "limited option."
猜猜是哪一个？我会给你一个“有限的选择”。
Excuse me, sir.
对不起，先生。
Allow me.
请允许我。
I apologize
on his behalf for the--
我代表他向你道歉
Why?
为什么?
That really hurt.
真的很痛。
What'd you expect?
He's metal.
你想要什么？他是金属。
You know you were
out of line,
你知道你太过分了，
talking back
to a superior like that.
跟上级顶嘴。
Darkwing was out of line.
He deserves it.
暗翼太过分了。这是他应得的。
Aren't you tired of being
treated like we're nothing?
你难道不厌倦我们被当作废物对待吗？
He had every right
to hit me.
I interfered.
他完全有权利打我。我干扰。
Hey, and I appreciate
you having my back.
我很感激你支持我。
I'm glad
you were there with me
我很高兴你和我在一起
to get punched in the face.
That was fun.
被人打脸。那很有趣。
Anytime, buddy.
随时,老兄。
Attention, all sectors.
各部门请注意。
Stand by for
a live transmission
from Sentinel Prime.
等待哨兵Prime的实时传输。
He's back?
He's back already?
Maybe he found the Matrix.
他回来了吗?他已经回来了？也许他找到母体了。
Is it on? Okay, thank you.
开了吗？好的，谢谢。
Hello, my friends.
大家好。
Hello, Iacon City!
你好，Iacon市！
Hello to our saviors,
the industrious miners
向我们的救星，勤劳的矿工们问好
who toil selflessly to maintain
our Energon reserves.
他们无私地辛勤劳作以维持我们的能源储备。
I celebrate you.
我为你庆祝。
Humility and presence!
That's leadership!
谦卑和风度！这是领导!
Ah! Nobody does it better!
啊!没有人做得更好！
Once again, I have narrowly
returned with my fleet
再一次，我带着我的舰队险胜返回
after another
treacherous expedition
在另一次危险的探险之后
across the desolate, dangerous
surface of our planet.
穿越我们星球荒凉、危险的表面。
I departed with hopes
of finding
the Matrix of Leadership,
我带着找到领导矩阵的希望离开了，
the key to bringing balance
to Cybertron.
为塞伯坦带来平衡的关键。
I regret to inform you
我很遗憾地通知你
that we've
returned empty-handed.
我们空手而归。
This is a setback,
but not a failure.
这是一次挫折，但不是失败。
Rest assured, I will find
the Matrix of Leadership,
请放心，我会找到领导力矩阵，
so that Energon can flow again.
使Energon可以再次流动。
But that's in the future.
但那是将来的事。
Right now,
I think we all
deserve a little fun!
现在，我想我们都应该有一点乐趣！
Tomorrow,
there will be no work.
All shifts off
明天，将没有工作。
because tomorrow
is the Iacon 5000!
因为明天是Iacon 5000！
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
哇!Whoo-hoo !
My favorite event.
我最喜欢的活动。
A high-octane race
all across Iacon City.
一场横跨Iacon市的高强度比赛。
Let's all see which competitor
can prove they are truly
more than meets the eye.
让我们来看看哪位竞争者能证明他们真的比表面上看起来的要好。
D.
D。
Psst! Hey, D.
嘘!嘿,D。
Oh, good, you're up.
Come on, I have an idea.
太好了，你起来了。来吧，我有个主意。
Whatever this is,
it better be good.
不管这是什么，最好是好事。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. Listen.
对，对，对，对。好吧。听。
All right, what if...
what if...
好吧，如果……如果……
what if tomorrow
如果明天呢？
we ran
in the Iacon 5000, huh?
我们开的是Iacon 5000 ？
What if kill you
for waking me up?
不如杀了你，因为你吵醒了我？
No, no, no, hear me out.
不，不，不，听我说完。
We don't even have to win!
我们甚至不需要赢！
Oh, that's good,
because we wouldn't.
太好了，因为我们不会。
But-- But if we beat
just one Transformer,
但如果我们能打败一个变形金刚，
it proves
we're just as good as they are.
这证明我们和他们一样优秀。
Not only would we
go down in history,
我们不仅会被载入史册，
the mining bots
that did the impossible,
采矿机器人完成了不可能的任务，
but we would show everyone
that we're--
但我们会向所有人展示我们是
we're capable
of so much more!
我们有能力做更多！
Or we get
publicly humiliated
否则我们会被公开羞辱
and then busted
back to tier one.
然后又回到了第一层。
Yeah, but at least we would've
done something, you know?
是啊，但至少我们会做点什么？
Pax...
Come on, D.
罗马帝国……得了吧，D。
Pax.
Pax。
We're mining bots
who can't transform.
我们是不会变形的采矿机器人。
We can't fly,
we can't roll,
我们不能飞，我们不能滚，
we can't race.
我们不能比赛。
Come on, let's go.
来吧，我们走。
All right, fine.
好吧，没问题。
Yeah, maybe you're right.
也许你是对的。
Maybe.
也许吧。
The Iacon 5000
is finally here!
Iacon 5000终于来了！
I have a surprise
for you. Come on.
我有个惊喜要给你。来吧。
Where are you going?
The stadium's that way.
你要去哪里？体育馆在那边。
Yeah, yeah, I know.
Follow me.
是的，是的，我知道。跟我来。
Great.
We're gonna be late now.
太好了。我们要迟到了。
I wanted good seats.
我想要好座位。
We came all this way to miss
the opening ceremony.
This is wonderful!
我们大老远来就是为了错过开幕式。这太棒了！
Trust me,
I know what I'm doing.
相信我，我知道我在做什么。
Hold up!
举起!
Get caught in one of those,
it'll launch you
halfway across the city.
如果被困在其中，你就会被炸飞半个城市。
Okay,
where are you taking me?
好吧，你要带我去哪？
Don't be a glitch, this will be
totally worth it. Trust me.
别犯傻了，这绝对值得。相信我。
Hey, you don't be a glitch.
嘿，你不是个小故障。
Look, I know this is, like,
fun for you,
我知道这对你来说很有趣，
like, we're joking around,
就像我们在开玩笑，
but if you make me miss
any part of the Iacon 5000,
但如果你让我错过了艾康5000的任何部分
I swear I will smelt
your face right off your...
我发誓我会从你的…
Welcome to the Iacon 5000.
There they are.
欢迎来到Iacon 5000。
Put your hands together
as today's competitors
are taking the field.
把你的手放在一起，因为今天的竞争对手正在领跑。
Look! There's
Thunderglide and Behemoth!
看！有迅雷滑翔和巨兽！
This is unbelievable!
I feel like I'm in the race!
真是难以置信！我觉得我在比赛！
You did this for me?
你这么做是为了我？
No.
不。
I did this for us.
我这么做是为了我们。
And now the moment
you've all been waiting for.
现在是你们期待已久的时刻。
The icon of Iacon!
icon的图标！
The savior of Cybertron!
塞伯坦的救世主！
Quintessons fear him,
but we love him!
学生害怕他，但我们爱他！
Our leader,
the one and only...
我们的领袖，独一无二的…
Sentinel Prime!
哨兵' !
I love you, Sentinel!
我爱你，哨兵！
Yes! It feels so good
to be here with you all today.
是的!今天和大家在一起感觉很好。
My friends.
My Cybertronian family.
我的朋友。我的塞伯坦家族。
It has been
precisely 50 cycles
正好是50个周期
since the Quintessons
attacked our home.
自从Quintessons袭击我们家之后
Fifty cycles since we lost
the Matrix of Leadership
自从我们失去领导力矩阵已经有50个周期了
and our Energon supply
dried up.
我们的能源供应枯竭。
Fifty cycles since the battle
that killed the other Primes,
从杀死其他超级战士的战斗开始已经过去了50个周期，
my brothers
and sisters in arms.
我的兄弟姐妹们。
Today we honor the Primes
who gave their lives for ours
今天我们向为我们牺牲生命的超级英雄致敬
and we show them
that the strength of Cybertron
will never be diminished.
让他们知道塞伯坦的力量永远不会被削弱。
Racers, on your marks!
选手们，各就各位！
I can't believe we get to watch
from the starting line.
真不敢相信我们能站在起跑线上观看比赛。
The best seats
in the house!
最好的座位！
Why'd you bring jetpacks?
你为什么带着喷气背包？
Get set!
设置!
It's time to show them
we are more than meets the eye.
是时候向他们展示我们的真面目了。
Oh, no.
哦,不。
And they're off!
他们走了！
Are you crazy?
Sure feels like it.
你疯了吗？感觉就是这样。
The Iacon 5000 has begun!
icon 5000已经开始了！
I'm sorry, are those
miners in the race?
抱歉，那些矿工也在竞选吗？
Miners!
Those are miners,
like us!
矿工!他们是矿工，和我们一样！
I can't believe
what I'm seeing here!
Miners trying to run
我简直不敢相信我在这里看到的！试图运行的矿工
in the Iacon 5000!
You've got to be kidding me.
在Iacon 5000！你一定是在开玩笑。
This is insane!
这太疯狂了！
There are miners
in the race!
Miners?
比赛中有矿工！矿工吗?
No way!
They can't even transform!
没门!他们连变形都不会！
It's Orion Pax and D-16!
这是猎户座帕克斯和D-16！
This is a first
in Iacon 5000 history.
这是Iacon 5000历史上的第一次。
How are they going to survive?
他们将如何生存？
If we survive this,
I'm gonna kill you!
如果我们能活下来，我就杀了你！
I accept those terms.
我接受这些条件。
It's Tailwind
pulling into the lead
down the main stretch
顺风在主拉伸段拉入领先位置
followed by Strafe and Skyfire!
后面是Strafe和Skyfire！
Hey, look out!
嘿，小心！
I owe you one.
More like a thousand.
我欠你一个人情。更像是一千。
I can't believe
we're not in last place!
真不敢相信我们不是最后一名！
Eat it, miner!
吃吧，矿工！
Darkwing delivers
a devastating blow!
Gotcha!
黑暗之翼带来毁灭性的打击！问题!
We're not fast enough!
Improvise!
我们不够快！即兴创作!
Hey! Get off!
Spinout! Big fan!
嘿!下车!分拆等!大风扇!
Hey!
Jetstorm, I'm so sorry.
Big fan!
嘿!喷气风暴，我很抱歉。大风扇!
Get off!
下车!
Time it just right!
时间刚刚好！
And... now!
和…现在!
Move!
动!
And the miners
have fallen way behind.
矿工们已经远远落在后面了。
We can now focus
on the real contenders
in this race.
我们现在可以关注这场比赛中真正的竞争者了。
I don't believe it!
The miners take down Darkwing!
我不相信！矿工们干掉暗翼！
Oh, miners!
哦,矿工!
Great effort,
Darkwing!
干得好，暗翼！
That worked!
It actually worked!
那工作!它真的起作用了！
Is this the dumbest thing
we've ever done?
这是我们做过的最蠢的事吗？
Oh, yeah, it's up there!
哦，是的，它在上面！
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
Whoa!
哇!
Wait!
等等!
Go, go, go!
快，快，快！
A four-bot pileup
in the magnetic tunnel
磁隧道中四车连环相撞
and the two miners are now
in first position!
和两个矿工现在在第一位置！
This is unbelievable!
这太不可思议了！
Ah!
啊!
D!
D !
No. Go. Leave me!
不。走了。离开我!
No, we do this together.
不，我们一起做。
One miner is now
carrying the other
一个矿工正在搬运另一个矿工
mere steps
from the finish line
距离终点线仅几步之遥
in the most amazing,
sensational, dramatic,
heartrending, exciting,
在最惊人的，耸人听闻的，戏剧性的，令人心碎的，激动人心的，
thrilling finish
in the history of--
历史上惊心动魄的结局——
We have a winner!
我们有赢家了！
Chromia comes from behind
to take the prize.
Chromia后来居上。
Talk about an Iacon 5000
for the ages.
谈谈一款经久不衰的icon 5000。
Well, second place
is still pretty good.
第二名还是不错的。
Paging Dr. Ratchet.
Dr. Ratchet to Medical Bay 94.
呼叫棘轮医生。棘轮医生到医疗湾。
Do not worry.
You will be fixed up
in no time.
别担心。你很快就会好起来的。
Did I win?
我赢了吗？
You participated.
你参加了。
Yay!
耶!
So...
所以…
how long do you think
we'll be here?
你觉得我们要在这里待多久？
I'm not talking to you.
我不会跟你说话的。
You know what?
I can't believe
you made me do that.
你知道吗？真不敢相信你让我这么做。
We are so screwed!
Thought you weren't
talking to me.
我们完蛋了！我以为你不和我说话了。
Hey, look, I know
it's all a big joke to you.
But not me.
听着，我知道这对你来说是个大笑话。但我不是。
I was paying my dues.
I was going places.
我付了我的会费。我要去很多地方。
And now they're gonna
bust me down
现在他们要把我抓起来
I-- I don't even know
how many tiers!
我都不知道有几层！
I'm sorry, D.
对不起，D。
But come on,
didn't you feel it?
拜托，你感觉不到吗？
Even for just a second,
didn't you feel liberated?
哪怕只有一秒钟，你不觉得解放了吗？
Didn't you feel like
you were something else?
难道你不觉得自己是另一个人吗？
Like you could be more
than what they say you are?
好像你能比他们说的更好吗？
Yeah, I felt it. I did.
是的，我感觉到了。我做到了。
But it doesn't matter.
但没关系。
We're going to get
punished and demoted.
我们会受到惩罚，被降职。
Sentinel Prime
saw the whole thing.
哨兵擎天看到了整个过程。
This is so embarrassing.
这太尴尬了。
It's clear.
很明显。
Orion Pax.
猎户座Pax。
D-16.
D-16。
What you two did today
你们俩今天干了什么
was one of the
craziest things
I've ever seen.
是我见过的最疯狂的事情之一
Sir, this is all my idea,
and we're so sorry.
先生，这都是我的主意，我们很抱歉。
I loved it!
我喜欢它！
You did?
你做了吗?
How could anyone
not love it?
怎么会有人不喜欢呢？
You gave my best racers
a real run for their money.
你给了我最好的车手一场真正的比赛。
So we're not
getting demoted?
所以我们不会被降职？
Demoted?
降级?
Demoted.
降级。
What is happening?
发生了什么？
The fact of the matter
is we're halfway
into the first shift
事实是我们第一班才上了一半
since the race ended
and that mining crew
has already reached 150% quota.
自从比赛结束，采矿人员已经达到了150%的配额。
You inspired them
to work harder!
你激励他们更加努力工作！
Sentinel Prime, sir,
哨兵一号，长官，
we joined the race
to show everyone our potential.
我们参加比赛是为了向大家展示我们的潜力。
That we bots can do
more than just mine--
我们机器人能做的不仅仅是我的
Outstanding! I love a bot
that can think for himself.
杰出的!我喜欢能独立思考的机器人。
Perhaps you two
could tour the mines,
也许你们俩可以参观一下矿场，
speak to your brethren, and
help them see their potential.
和你的兄弟们谈谈，帮助他们看到自己的潜力。
Wow! Okay, great.
哇!好了,好了。
That sounds incredible.
听起来不可思议。
I would love to--
Sir, it's time.
我很乐意先生，时间到了。
Ah, yes.
啊,是的。
I'm sorry, friends.
对不起，朋友们。
We're preparing
our next travel
to the surface.
我们在准备下一次的地表之旅。
But in the meantime,
I've got a treat for you.
但与此同时，我要招待你。
Hang tight.
Airachnid, have someone
escort these heroes
挂紧。蜘蛛，派人护送这些英雄
to my personal
service facilities.
我的私人服务设施。
Best care in Iacon.
在Iacon得到最好的照顾。
Until next time, legends.
下节课见，传奇。
Sentinel Prime.
The Sentinel Prime!
哨兵撇。擎天柱哨兵！
You still mad at me?
I am less mad at you.
你还在生我的气？我没那么生你的气了。
I'm telling you, D--
I got a feeling
that everything's gonna change
我跟你说，小迪，我有种感觉一切都会改变
and we're gonna go--
我们要去
Miners!
矿工!
Hi, Darkwing.
嗨,Darkwing。
Oh, no, no, no.
No!
哦，不，不，不。不!
Wait, wait!
You don't understand!
等等,等等!你不明白！
We were supposed to go
to Sentinel Prime's service pod!
我们应该去哨兵擎天柱的服务舱！
You two dolts aren't going
to see anyone ever again.
你们两个笨蛋再也见不到人了。
I'll make sure of that.
我会确保的。
You're making a mistake!
Ask Sentinel!
你搞错了！问哨兵!
I hate that guy!
我讨厌那个家伙！
You! How did you get down here?
你!你是怎么下来的？
There's no access to this level.
无法进入这一层。
There is nobody
down here but me.
这里除了我没人。
Oh, my gosh, you're real!
天啊，你是真的！
You're others!
You're not... me!
你是别人的!你不是…我!
You're here,
and you're not me!
你在这里，你不是我！
Uh, yeah.
Awesome!
嗯,是的。太棒了!
I am so sorry. That must
have been weird for you.
我很抱歉。那对你来说一定很奇怪。
I just haven't had
a lot of company
我只是没几个人陪我
since they put me
down here in sublevel 50.
从他们把我关在50层开始。
Fifty? But there
are only 40 sublevels.
五十?但是只有40个子级别。
That's what I thought!
我也是这么想的！
Turns out there are ten more,
and they are not pleasant.
原来还有十多只，而且都不讨人喜欢。
Probably why nobody ever
really talks about them.
也许这就是为什么没有人真正谈论它们的原因。
How long have you
been down here?
你在这里多久了？
How long have I been here?
我在这里多久了？
Let's see, somewhere
between a long time and forever?
让我想想，在很长一段时间和永远之间？
I mean, I had other jobs,
but I kept getting reassigned
我是说，我有其他工作，但我一直被重新分配
'cause I'm so good
at what I do.
因为我很擅长我的工作。
Oh! I'm B-127, by the way.
哦!顺便说一下，我是B-127。
But you can call me B.
但是你可以叫我B。
And I'm actually
working on some nicknames.
我还在想一些昵称呢。
The one I'm floating right now
is Badassatron.
我现在漂浮的那个是巴达萨天。
Which is actually pronounced...
"Badassatron."
实际上发音是…“Badassatron。”
But if you have any critiques--
但如果你有任何意见
Yeah, great.
How do we get
out of here?
是的,很好。我们怎么离开这里？
Great question. You don't.
好问题。你不。
We don't?
Nope.
我们不?不。
We have limited access
to the waste management area,
我们进入垃圾管理区的权限有限，
but the new shift manager there
does not like distractions.
但那里的新轮班经理不喜欢分心。
No, they prefer we stay here
on the task at hand.
不，他们更希望我们留在这里完成手头的任务。
Which is?
Oh!
是哪一个?哦!
The scrap comes in
from the chute there
废料从那里的斜槽进来
onto the conveyor belt.
放到传送带上。
Our job is to look for anything
that might be worth salvaging
我们的工作是寻找任何可能值得打捞的东西
before it hits the furnace
and gets smelted.
在它进入熔炉被熔炼之前。
So you watch garbage burn.
所以你看着垃圾燃烧。
Yes!
是的!
It is so great
that you're here now.
你能来真是太好了。
I can't wait to learn
everything about you.
我迫不及待地想了解你的一切。
And then tell you
everything about me!
然后告诉你关于我的一切！
I have a lot of hopes and dreams
that I am just dying to share
我有很多希望和梦想，我很想和大家分享
with one or two
new best friends.
和一两个新的好朋友。
Uh, yeah, I would love to--
是啊，我很乐意
Where are my manners?
我的礼貌哪儿去了？
Come on, I'll introduce you
to the rest of the crew.
来吧，我把你介绍给其他船员。
Hey, guys, we've got company!
伙计们，有人来了！
This is EP-508,
这是EP-508，
this is A-A-Tron,
and this fella here is Steve.
这是A-A-Tron，这位是Steve。
"Steve"?
Yeah, he's foreign.
“乔布斯”?是的，他是外国人。
Do they talk back to you?
他们会和你顶嘴吗？
Um, they're not real.
嗯，他们不是真的。
Jeez, you think I'm that crazy?
天啊，你觉得我有那么疯狂吗？
It's just
you've been down here a--
只是你在这里待了这么久
No, I was talking to Steve.
不，我在和史蒂夫说话。
Classic Steve.
经典的史蒂夫。
What is that?
Look at this guy.
那是什么？看看这个家伙。
It's coming from inside.
它是从内部发出的。
Oh! Steve! No!
哦!史蒂夫!不!
I am so sorry.
Steve, no!
我很抱歉。史蒂夫,不!
We can fix it, don't worry.
My Steve!
我们能修好的，别担心。我的史蒂夫!
Quintesson ambush!
Quintesson伏击!
Calling the High Guard
for immediate support.
Immediate support!
呼叫高级警卫立即支援。直接支持!
That's Alpha Trion.
那是阿尔法狮。
One of the Primes?
超级英雄之一？
Repeat,
Zeta Prime has fallen!
重复，泽塔擎天柱倒下了！
It's an SOS message.
Protect the Matrix!
这是一条SOS信息。保护矩阵！
Sending location coordinates.
发送位置坐标。发送位置坐标。
Holy Primus!
天博智!
Those are coordinates
to a location on the surface.
这些是地表上某个位置的坐标。
This could be
where the Primes died
in the Quintesson war.
这里可能是擎天柱在Quintesson战争中死去的地方。
Which means
this is where we could find
也就是说我们可以在这里找到
the Matrix of Leadership.
《领导力矩阵》
What are you talking about?
It's an old beacon
inside a statue made of garbage.
你在说什么？这是一个在垃圾雕像里的旧灯塔。
Or it's a clue
of how we could find
或者这是我们如何找到的线索
the Matrix of Leadership.
No. No way. Absolutely not!
《领导力矩阵》不。不可能。绝对不是!
Hey, D, come on,
this could be our chance
to show everyone we're not--
D，别这样，这是我们向大家展示我们不是…的机会
You already tried
to "show everyone"
你已经试着“向所有人展示”了
in the race
you tricked me
into running,
在你骗我参加的比赛中，
which got us
stuck down here
是什么把我们困在这里的
in this waste hole
with this, uh...
在这个废物坑里，拿着这个…
really cool guy.
很酷的家伙。
Oh, thank you.
I'm just saying--
哦，谢谢。我只是说——
There's a reason
no one goes
to the surface.
没人去地表是有原因的。
It's dangerous!
是很危险的!
I'm waiting right here
until Sentinel Prime
finds us.
我就在这里等着哨兵擎天柱找到我们。
Oh, okay. Yeah. Hmm.
哦,好的。是的。嗯。
Well, we'll just
stay here forever.
That cool with you, B?
好吧，我们就永远呆在这里。你没意见吧，B？
Forever? This is great!
到永远吗?这太棒了！
I have new coworkers
and roommates.
我有了新的同事和室友。
There's plenty of room
now that Steve is dead.
既然史蒂夫死了，还有很多空间。
I usually sleep
on the conveyor belt,
but you can totally have it.
我通常睡在传送带上，但你完全可以睡。
I'll sleep in the corner
next to A-A-Tron.
我会睡在阿创旁边的角落。
Plenty of room
for you to stretch out, too,
也有足够的空间让你伸展身体，
'cause you're taller than I am.
Know what I mean?
因为你比我高。明白我的意思吗？
Hey, D, what do you think
Sentinel's reaction would be
if you personally handed him
D，你觉得如果你亲自交给哨兵他会有什么反应
the Matrix of Leadership
that you found?
你发现的领导力矩阵？
Okay, stop.
I know what you're
trying to do.
好了,停止。我知道你想干什么。
And it's
definitely working.
I'm in.
这绝对是有效的。我在。
Hah, ha! Yeah, buddy.
How do we get
to the surface?
哈,哈!是的,朋友。我们怎么到地面上去？
Pfft! You kidding me?
The surface?
啐!开什么玩笑？表面吗?
Easy. I know a way.
一件容易的事。我知道一个办法。
But it won't be easy.
但这并不容易。
Why is there so much trash? Ah!
为什么有这么多垃圾？啊!
Warn me
next time, please.
My mouth was open.
下次请提醒我。我张着嘴。
Only 49 sublevels to go!
只有49个子级别去！
Waste-disposal trains
are the only vehicles
废物处理列车是唯一的交通工具
that go all the way
to the surface.
一直延伸到表面。
Yeah, but they
don't allow passengers.
The trains are autonomous.
是的，但是他们不让乘客进去。火车是自动驾驶的。
Yeah, that's the
"won't be easy" part.
是啊，这就是“不容易”的部分。
It's perfect.
We'll be safe
inside the train.
它是完美的。我们在火车里是安全的。
That's the last one.
Send 'er up!
这是最后一个。让她上来！
Hold up! One more.
举起!一个。
I'll lock it down.
我会把它锁起来的。
Thanks for being an idiot,
whoever you are.
不管你是谁，谢谢你这么傻。
Turning you in will
definitely get me promoted
back up a rank or two.
告发你肯定能让我升回一两个级别。
Got her!
了她!
No, wait, I--
不，等等，我
Elita! Stop!
Elita !停!
Orion?
Hold on, let me--
猎户星座吗?等等，让我——
Security! Sound the ala--
安全!发出ala的声音——
She's headed to the engine!
Don't worry, I got this.
她往引擎那边去了！别担心，我能行。
Hold on, let me explain!
We're on a mission!
等等，让我解释一下！我们在执行任务！
So am I. To ruin your life.
我也是，毁了你的生活。
Elita, wait. We found a message.
We know where--
Elita等。我们发现了一条信息。我们知道——
This bot is crazy! Who is she?
这个机器人疯了！她是谁？
Dead end, Elita.
There's no way...
死路一条，伊莉塔。不可能……
Well, she's gone.
好吧，她走了。
Whoa!
哇!
Why? Why am I doing this?
Why am I doing this?
为什么?我为什么要这么做？我为什么要这么做？
Climb faster!
快爬!
Gotcha!
明白了!
Ah, the surface.
啊，表面。
It's beautiful.
它是美丽的。
I am speechless.
我无语了。
Elita, listen to me.
伊莉塔，听我说。
We know where
the Matrix of Leadership is.
我们知道领导力矩阵在哪里。
Oh, sure.
And I'm really a Prime.
哦,当然。我真的是Prime会员。
I just prefer loading
crates of toxic waste.
我只是更喜欢装一箱箱有毒废物。
Whoa.
Where did you get this?
哇。你从哪儿弄来的？
From my friend Steve.
Orion killed him.
来自我的朋友史蒂夫。俄里翁杀了他。
I did not kill Steve.
He was never alive.
我没有杀史蒂夫。他从未活过。
What?
Look.
怎么啦？看。
Sentinel told us
he was going to the surface,
哨兵告诉我们他要去地表，
and then we found this message.
然后我们发现了这个信息。
We figured that we could
hand deliver it to him
我们想我们可以亲手交给他
or scout
the locations ourselves.
或者我们自己去侦察地点。
Whichever comes first.
先到的那个。
This was too important to wait.
这件事太重要了，不能再等了。
It will change all of our lives.
它将改变我们所有人的生活。
No, no, no, no.
不，不，不。
I'm not going to get demoted
again because of you.
我不会再因为你被降职了。
I'm turning this rig around
and I'm notifying the--
我要调头，我要通知
Hey, guys? Guys?
嘿,伙计们?人吗?
What is that?
那是什么？
Is it getting bigger?
它越来越大了吗？
Or closer?
还是近?
No, no, no, no, no, no!
不，不，不，不！
Are you closing?
Don't close. Stop closing.
你们要打烊了吗？不要关闭。停止关闭。
It's closed!
它是封闭的!
Oh, come on!
哦，别这样！
Oh, now I know why
no one comes to the surface!
哦，现在我知道为什么没有人浮出水面了！
Elita?
Elita吗?
You okay?
你没事吧?
Please stop
punching me in the face.
别再打我的脸了。
Can you help?
你能帮忙吗？
Iacon-- The train--
艾康——火车——
Where's the train?
Relax, okay? Here it comes.
火车在哪里？放松,好吗?它来了。
And there it goes.
就这样。
Okay, I was wrong about that.
It was going the other way.
好吧，我错了。相反的方向。
Okay, so I think
this is us,
好吧，我想这就是我们，
and if we follow
the path to--
Now you listen to me,
如果我们沿着这条路走现在你听我说
Mr. "Zero Seconds
Since My Last Accident"!
先生。“距离上次事故零秒”！
I'll go on your little quest
because I don't have a choice.
我会继续你的小任务，因为我别无选择。
But I carry the map, I navigate,
and if this leads to nothing,
但我带着地图，我在导航，如果一无所获，
then I'm dragging you
and those two idiot go-bots
那我就拖着你和那两个白痴机器人
back to Iacon City
回到艾肯市
and to the first
supervisor depot we see,
我们看到的第一个监工仓库，
at which point you will explain
everything that's happened,
然后你就会解释发生的一切，
using words that reflect me
用能反映我的语言
in a very positive light!
Got it?
以一种非常积极的方式！明白了吗?
Yeah, okay.
Deal. Great. All right.
是的,好的。交易。太好了。好吧。
Let's go!
She's joining us?
我们走吧!她要加入我们？
Fantastic!
太棒了!
Hi there. Uh, Elita, right?
Am I saying that right?
嗨。呃，是埃莉塔，对吧？我说的对吗？
Wanted to formally
introduce myself.
我想正式介绍一下我自己。
I'm B-127. You kneed me
in the face earlier, back there.
我是b - 127。你之前在那用膝盖打了我的脸。
You can call me B,
or Badassatron.
你可以叫我B，或者Badassatron。
It's a nickname
some of the guys gave me.
是一些人给我起的绰号。
I don't know. I didn't give it
to myself or anything.
我不知道。我不是给自己吃的。
Actually, it's pronounced...
"Badassatron,"
实际上，它的发音是……“Badassatron。”
in case you were wondering.
如果你想知道的话。
Badassatron.
Badassatron。
You like that, right?
你喜欢这样，对吧？
Badass--
I'm gonna need you
to talk less.
混蛋，我要你少说话。
Sure! No-- Yeah, no problem.
当然!不——是的，没问题。
What am I talking less about,
my nickname?
我少说了什么，我的昵称吗？
That's fine with me.
Got some mountains over here...
我没意见。这里有一些山…
Hey. You're thinking
about what you'll say
嘿。你在想你要说什么
when you hand the Matrix
to Sentinel, aren't you?
当你把母体交给哨兵时，是吗？
I can't help it.
我没办法。
D, we're really doing this.
D，我们真的在做这个。
So glad
I'm out here with you.
This was a great idea.
很高兴能和你在一起。这是个好主意。
I'm just having a good time.
我只是玩得很开心。
How much further
is the Matrix on the map?
矩阵在地图上还有多远？
Make an educated guesstimate.
做一个有根据的猜测。
This is the coolest thing
that has ever happened
这是发生过的最酷的事
to anyone anywhere,
I'm telling you!
给任何人，任何地方，我告诉你！
♪ Not one, not two
Not three, but four ♪
不是一个，不是两个不是三个，而是四个
♪ Four best friends who are
Walking through the door ♪
四个最好的朋友走在门口♬
There's no doors,
we're outside.
没有门，我们在外面。
Hey, look,
there's more of it over here.
嘿，看，这里还有更多。
What is it?
It's not metal.
这是什么？它不是金属。
It's like some kind
of weird nature. It's weird.
就像某种奇怪的天性。这很奇怪。
So are they.
他们也是。
♪ Going to the Matrix ♪
去矩阵♬
♪ With my best friends ♪
♬和我最好的朋友在一起♬
What was that?
那是什么？
Um...
嗯…
I think this is not right.
We should go.
我觉得这样不对。我们该走了。
Yeah, good idea.
Run!
好主意。快跑!
What are we running from?
我们在逃避什么？
What is that?
Oh, no.
那是什么？哦,不。
It's a Quintesson ship.
What?
这是一艘Quintesson船。怎么啦？
What do we do?
Shh! Quiet.
我们该怎么办？我们该怎么办？嘘!安静。
It's scanning for life-forms.
Move, move!
它在扫描生命形式。动,动!
Wait!
等等!
Go, go, go, go!
快，快，快，快！
Come on!
来吧!
They're not gonna make it.
他们不会成功的。
Whoa.
哇。
What-- What were they
searching for?
他们在找什么？
Someone to hug, B.
How should I know?
B.我怎么知道？
I'm not waiting around
to find out.
我不会等着发现的。
This way.
We're close.
这种方式。我们接近。
Quintessons haven't
been here for 50 cycles.
Quintessons已经有50个周期没来了。
It doesn't make sense.
There's nothing out here.
这说不通啊。外面什么都没有。
A cave with teeth.
Nothing scary about that.
有牙齿的洞穴。没什么可怕的。
Knives coming
out of the ceiling. Amazing.
刀子从天花板上冒出来。很神奇的。
Everyone,
do we have to go insi--?
各位，我们一定要进去吗？
Okay, yep, we're going in.
好了，我们要进去了。
Why shouldn't we? Just walking
into the scariest place
为什么不能呢？走进了最可怕的地方
I've ever seen
in my entire life.
我这辈子见过的最好的。
This is ridiculous.
这太荒谬了。
I don't believe it.
我不相信。
The Primes.
质数。
We're here.
我们在这里。
Megatronus Prime.
Megatronus撇。
Zeta Prime.
ζ撇。
The Matrix!
矩阵!
It's gone.
这是一去不复返了。
Let's keep looking.
我们继续找。
Hey, guys!
嘿,伙计们!
It's Alpha Trion!
是阿尔法狮王！
He's powered down.
他断电了。
But his spark is still lit.
但他身上的火花仍未熄灭。
Quintesson ambush!
Quintesson伏击!
Attack!
攻击!
Message before--
消息之前,
Whoa, whoa, it's okay!
It's okay.
哇，哇，没事的！没关系。
You're safe now.
你现在安全了。
The war is over.
战争结束了。
I failed you, old friend.
我让你失望了，老朋友。
You deserved
so much better than this end.
你不该落得这样的下场。
No, you didn't fail.
不，你没有失败。
We heard your message.
We've come to find
the Matrix.
我们听到了你的留言。我们是来找母体的。
Your transformation cogs.
What happened to you?
你的转变很顺利。你怎么了？
Who are you?
你是谁？
We're cogless miners,
from Iacon.
我们是没有齿轮的矿工，来自艾肯。
Miners? Why?
矿工吗?为什么?
Well, we've had
to drill for Energon
我们不得不为能源公司钻探
ever since
it stopped flowing.
自从它停止流动。
Impossible.
不可能的。
That's why we came.
To fix things.
这就是我们来的原因。去解决问题。
If we find
the Matrix of Leadership
如果我们找到领导矩阵
and get it to Sentinel Prime,
he can fix--
把它交给哨兵擎天柱，他就能修好
Sentinel is no Prime.
哨兵不是王者。
What?
He's broken.
Fantastic.
怎么啦？他是坏了。太棒了。
What are you talking about?
Why would you say that?
你在说什么？你为什么这么说？
Sentinel Prime
is our protector.
守护者是我们的保护者。
He's been saving us from
the Quintessons ever since--
从那以后他就一直把我们从Quintessons手中拯救出来
You have not been saved.
You've been living a lie.
你还没有得救。你一直活在谎言中。
I saw the truth
with my own eyes.
我亲眼看到了真相。
Come. I will show you.
来了。我来告诉你。
For thousands of cycles,
the war with the Quintessons
数千个轮回，与五世会的战争
had been a brutal conflict.
这是一场残酷的冲突。
Until Sentinel,
the principal aide
to the Primes,
直到哨兵，质数的主要助手，
intercepted an enemy transmission.
截获了敌人的信号。
There was going to be
a secret gathering
of Quintesson commanders.
将有一个Quintesson指挥官的秘密聚会。
Their elimination
could end the war.
消灭他们可以结束战争。
It was a mission so important,
we Primes took it on ourselves.
这是一项非常重要的任务，我们擎天柱自己承担了。
We agreed to meet Sentinel for
his sensitive intel in secret,
我们同意秘密会见哨兵获取他的敏感情报，
here in this cave.
就在这个山洞里。
But we were not alone.
但我们并不孤单。
Quintessons!
They're here!
Quintessons !他们在这里!
It's a trap!
Battle positions!
这是个陷阱！战斗位置!
Hold the line!
Primus be with us!
别挂线！普里默斯与我们同在！
For Cybertron!
塞伯坦传奇!
We were outnumbered,
but stood as one.
我们寡不敌众，但团结一致。
Our victory was near.
我们就要胜利了。
Until we were betrayed.
直到我们被背叛。
Sentinel, why?
哨兵,为什么?
For all the power
of Cybertron.
不管塞伯坦有多强大。
But Sentinel never
understood the true power
of what he desired.
但是哨兵从来没有理解他所渴望的东西的真正力量。
The Matrix of Leadership
can only be wielded
领导矩阵只能被运用
by one that Primus himself
deems worthy.
被一个Primus自己认为值得的人。
And Sentinel
most certainly was not.
而Sentinel绝对不是。
No!
不!
Wait. Hold on. You're saying
that the Matrix of Leadership
just vanished?
等待。等一等。你是说《领导力矩阵》消失了？
No.
不。
No, no, no. That is impossible.
I don't believe it.
不，不，不。那是不可能的。我不相信。
Why would Sentinel
do that?
哨兵为什么要这么做？
To make a bargain.
做交易。
A bargain? With who?
讨价还价?与谁?
With the new rulers
of Cybertron.
塞伯坦的新统治者。
The Quintessons.
Quintessons。
There are so many.
有这么多。
He's here.
他在这里。
Sentinel Prime is here.
擎天柱哨兵来了。
Keep your eyes open.
They always are.
睁大你的眼睛。他们总是这样。
I load those crates.
我装那些箱子。
Those are filled
with contaminated metal.
里面装满了被污染的金属。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
What do the Quintessons
want with toxic waste?
Quintessons想用有毒废物做什么？
Our Energon.
我们的Energon。
Traitor!
D, no.
叛徒!D,没有。
I know what
I promised you
我知道我答应过你什么
but our mines,
they're running out!
但我们的地雷快用完了！
There's barely
enough Energon for us.
能量勉强够我们用。
I swear I will
get you the rest.
我发誓我会把剩下的给你。
Triple-time
every mining shift.
每次采矿班次增加三倍。
No miner gets a break
until I get my Energon.
在我拿到能量之前，所有矿工都不能休息。
All of it! Let's go.
全部！我们走吧。
Now you have seen the truth.
现在你看到了真相。
Every day...
每一天…
Every single day
of my life
我生命中的每一天
has been a lie.
一直都是谎言。
My God, I knew it!
天哪，我就知道！
Deep down,
I always felt
something was off.
内心深处，我总觉得不对劲。
He deceived everyone.
他欺骗了所有人。
Sentinel bought himself power
and then put us to work
paying off his debt.
哨兵给自己买了权力然后让我们帮他还债。
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信。
Well, obviously,
I can believe it,
很明显，我可以相信
I just saw it,
but I still...
我刚看到，但我还是…
I can't believe it.
我真不敢相信。
Sentinel lied
哨兵撒了谎
to my face.
It was all a sham.
当着我的面。这一切都是假的。
How could we
have been so gullible?
我们怎么会这么容易上当受骗？
Oh, this-- this is going
to change everything.
这，这将改变一切。
You just had to do it,
didn't you?
你必须这么做，不是吗？
Me? What did I do?
我吗?我做了什么？
You just had
to go to the surface,
你只要走到水面上，
had to enter the Iacon 5000.
必须进入Iacon 5000
You just had to break protocol!
你非得违反规定不可！
Who cares about protocol?
I do!
谁在乎协议？我做!
I care!
我在乎!
Because nothing bad happens
when you stay on protocol!
因为只要你遵纪守法就不会有什么坏事发生！
Sentinel Prime
has been forcing us
Sentinel Prime一直在逼迫我们
to work in the mines
until our gears strip,
在矿井里工作，直到我们的齿轮脱落，
and all the while he's been
giving the Energon away
to our greatest enemies!
而他却一直把能量器交给我们最大的敌人！
And what do you think
he's going to do to us
when he finds out that we know?
如果他发现我们知道了，你觉得他会怎么对我们？
I'm not thinking about
what he's going to do,
我没在想他会怎么做，
I'm thinking about
what we're going to do.
我在想我们该怎么做。
That's the whole thing!
这就是全部！
You're never thinking about
anything else, just yourself!
你从来不考虑别的，只考虑你自己！
Fantastic!
Another Orion Pax master plan.
I can't wait to hear this.
太棒了!另一个猎户座公园的总体规划。我等不及要听了。
Don't you want
to stop him?
你不想阻止他吗？
No, I want to kill him!
不，我要杀了他！
I want to put Sentinel in chains
我想把哨兵锁起来
and march him
through the mines
带他穿过矿井
so everyone can see him
for the false Prime that he is!
这样每个人都能看到他是假的擎天柱！
I want him to suffer
and then to die in darkness.
我想让他受苦，然后在黑暗中死去。
But we all know
that it doesn't matter
但我们都知道这并不重要
what I want, right, Pax?
我想要的，对吧，帕克斯？
The fact is,
we're just cogless bots. Right?
事实是，我们只是没有大脑的机器人。对吧?
We had limited options,
and now... now we have none.
我们的选择有限，而现在…现在我们没有了。
No son or daughter of Cybertron
is born without a cog.
塞伯坦的儿子和女儿都有齿轮。
Oh, yeah.
I've been with myself
since I came online,
哦,是的。自从我上网后，我一直和自己在一起，
and this slot's
always been empty.
这个位置一直是空的。
What are you saying?
Are you saying--
你在说什么？你是说——
No. No way.
Nobody could be that evil,
not even Sentinel.
不。不可能。没人会那么邪恶，哨兵也不行。
He removed your cogs
before you came online.
他在你上网前把你的齿轮拆了。
We were born with
transformation cogs,
but he...
我们生来就有变形的齿轮，但他…
He took them from us.
他从我们手中夺走了他们。
What defines a Transformer...
变压器的定义是什么？
...is not the cog
in his chest
…不是他胸口的齿轮吗
but the spark
that resides in their core.
而是他们内心深处的火花。
A spark that gives you the will
to make your world better.
给你意志让你的世界变得更美好的火花。
My fellow Primes had that spark.
我的同伴们也有这样的火花。
And I see their strength
in you.
我在你身上看到了他们的力量。
Take their cogs
and access
your full potential.
接受他们的建议，充分发挥你的潜力。
Prima.
表面上。
Onyx.
缟玛瑙。
Alchemist.
炼金术士。
Micronus.
Micronus。
Warriors of noble spirit,
loyalty, strength.
战士的精神高尚，忠诚，力量强大。
Their uniqueness
enhanced by these.
它们的独特性因此而增强。
They were one. You are one.
他们是一体的。你就是其中之一。
All are one!
一切都是一体的！
Wait. We have...
You-- You gave us...
等待。我们有…你给了我们…
The ability
to change your world.
改变世界的能力。
How you choose
to use that power
is up to you.
你选择如何使用这种力量取决于你自己。
They've found us.
他们找到我们了。
Oh, yes!
Time to fight back!
哦,是的!是时候反击了！
No. You must return to
Iacon City and alert everyone.
不。你必须回到艾肯城，通知所有人。
Embedded in this
are the records
I have shown you.
这里面有我给你们看的记录。
Use it to reveal the truth.
用它来揭露真相。
We will.
我们会的。
This tunnel leads
to the mountains.
这条隧道通向山里。
Cybertron's future
is in your hands.
塞伯坦的未来掌握在你手中。
We're out of time.
我们没时间了。
We got to move!
我们得走了！
Wait, we can't just
leave you here.
等等，我们不能把你丢在这里。
Your fight will come,
my friend.
你的战斗终将到来，我的朋友。
Primus has a purpose
for us all.
普里默斯对我们都有意义。
But this fight...
但是这场战斗……
This fight is mine.
这场战斗是我的。
Now go!
现在去!
Stand down, old timer.
退下，老家伙。
Ah. Old, you say?
啊。你是说老了？
Not too old for you.
对你来说不算太老。
We need to hurry!
我们得快点了！
I still think
we have better odds
我还是觉得我们胜算更大
fighting than outrunning them.
与他们搏斗，而不是逃避。
Wait! We have cogs.
We can transform now.
等等!我们有齿轮。我们现在可以变换了。
That's right.
Everyone ready?
I was born ready.
这是正确的。每个人都准备好了吗?我生来就准备好了。
On three. One--
三。一个——
Ah!
啊!
How do we use these things?
我们如何使用这些东西？
I don't know. Just try.
我不知道。只是试一试。
It's working. Ha! It's working!
这是工作。哈!这是工作!
My head! My head!
我的头!我的头!
Whoa!
哇!
Help! Help!
的帮助!的帮助!
This is not faster!
这不是更快！
Oh, come on!
哦，别这样！
And transform!
和转换!
Wheels! I need wheels!
轮子!我需要轮子！
Whoa.
哇。
Ha!
哈!
Oh, wow.
哦,哇。
We're alive!
I've never moved that fast.
我们活着!我从来没这么快过。
That was incredible!
Did you see me slide all over?
太不可思议了！你看到我全身滑倒了吗？
Yes!
是的!
Hey, whoa, buddy.
You okay?
嘿，老兄。你没事吧?
I'm great. Are you kidding me?
We can transform!
我很好。你在开玩笑吗？我们可以变形！
We transform!
我们变换!
Oh, hey! I know.
哦,嘿!我知道。
We're wasting time.
We have to get back to Iacon.
我们在浪费时间。我们得回去找艾康。
Looks like the fastest way
看起来是最快的方法
back to Iacon is--
Here, I got it.
回到Iacon是这里，我知道了。
Hey, what are you doing?
嘿，你在干什么？
Don't worry, I got it.
Yeah, but be careful.
别担心，我能行。是的，但是要小心。
Our proof is inside and
you're spilling it everywhere.
我们的证据在里面，你却洒得到处都是。
I... got... it.
我…得到了……它。
Okay.
好吧。
Follow me.
跟我来。
Alpha Trion!
α揣恩!
You are still alive.
Would you look at that?
你还活着。你看那个？
You look horrible.
你看起来很糟糕。
Traitor.
You are a disgrace.
叛徒。你真丢人。
Primus will surely--
Uh-huh. Yes. Shut up.
普里默斯肯定会——嗯哼。是的。闭嘴。
I seized an opportunity
to take control of my future.
我抓住机会掌控了自己的未来。
Anything to get
out of working for you
只要不为你工作就行
and that boring
council of elders.
还有那个无聊的长老会议。
Seriously,
I would watch you Primes
说真的，我会看你们超级英雄的
spend half the day
losing a war
花半天时间输掉一场战争
and the other half
sitting around waxing poetic
about loyalty and honor.
而另一半则坐在那里对忠诚和荣誉赞歌。
And now look at you.
现在看看你。
Hear my words:
You will fall.
听我说：你会倒下的。
And a new Prime will rise--
一个新的超级英雄将会崛起
There you go again.
你又来了。
I don't want to listen
to any more speeches.
我不想再听任何演讲了。
There were others
in the cave with you.
洞里还有其他人和你在一起。
Who are they?
他们是谁？
They are to be your undoing.
他们将是你的毁灭。
You've lost, Sentinel.
Nothing you can do--
你输了，哨兵。你什么也做不了
Oh, didn't I just say
no speeches?
我刚才不是说不许演讲吗？
You heard me, right?
你听到了，对吧？
This is what I'm talking about.
Unbelievable.
这就是我说的。难以置信。
All of them are like that.
So disrespectful.
他们都是这样的。那么无礼。
Okay. Hunt down the others.
好吧。追捕其他人。
With pleasure.
与快乐。
Hey, buddy.
嘿,哥们。
Oh. Hey.
哦。嘿。
You've been a little quiet.
Are you all right?
你最近有点沉默。你还好吗？
All I can think about
is Sentinel's smirking face.
我满脑子都是哨兵的假笑。
He must pay for what he's done.
Someone has to do something.
他必须为他的所作所为付出代价。总得有人做点什么。
We are. With Alpha's proof
inside that device,
we will show everyone the truth.
我们是来旅游的。阿尔法的证据在装置里，我们会向大家展示真相。
You honestly believe
it'll be that easy?
你真的认为会那么容易吗？
Iacon doesn't want
to hear the truth.
艾康不想听真相。
They worship Sentinel.
他们崇拜哨兵。
There's got to be
a better way
to bring him down.
一定有更好的办法扳倒他。
We have to trust everyone will
believe what we show them.
我们必须相信每个人都会相信我们展示给他们的东西。
I trusted Sentinel!
我信任哨兵！
With everything.
与一切。
I will never trust
a so-called leader ever again.
我再也不会相信所谓的领袖了。
There's only one bot
I know I can trust--
我只知道我能信任一个人
All right,
wake them up.
好吧，把他们叫醒。
Now, are you spies
你们是间谍吗
or just incompetent lackeys?
或者只是不称职的走狗？
We're not spies.
But he is incompetent.
我们不是间谍。但他无能。
Scanning electrical impulses.
He speaks the truth.
扫描电脉冲。他说的是真话。
That just means
he believes himself,
like any spy would.
这只能说明他相信自己，就像其他间谍一样。
Uh, why is he gagged?
他为什么被堵住了嘴？
He wouldn't stop talking.
他不停地说话。
Even when he was
unconscious?
即使在他失去知觉的时候？
Especially when
he was unconscious!
尤其是当他失去知觉的时候！
Enough!
够了!
Two options for you!
你有两个选择！
One, we slowly
dismantle each of you
one bolt and screw at a time,
第一，我们慢慢地拆下你们每个人一个螺栓一个螺钉，
and really make sure
you feel it.
一定要感觉到。
Or two:
两个:
In exchange
for a quick death,
为了让我死得痛快
you give us intel
on the Energon trains,
你给我们能量列车的情报，
access to the mines
进入矿井
or anything else that could
hurt your boss, Sentinel Prime.
或者任何可能伤害你上司的事，哨兵擎天柱。
Who exactly are you guys?
你们到底是谁？
Ah!
啊!
The Cybertronian High Guard!
塞伯坦最高卫队！
I told you
it wasn't tight enough!
我就说不够紧吧！
Prestigious defenders
of Iacon.
Prestigious?
著名的伊肯的捍卫者。著名的?
He's right.
I read all about you
in the archives.
他是对的。我在档案里看到了你的一切。
You were
the most legendary warriors
in all of Cybertron.
你们是塞伯坦最具传奇色彩的战士。
Look, look, look!
That's Starscream,
看，看，看！红蜘蛛,
and you're Shockwave,
and Soundwave.
你们是冲击波和声波。
Raise your hand
if "wave" is in your name.
There's a lot of "waves."
如果你的名字里有“wave”，请举手。有很多“波浪”。
Silence!
安静!
The yellow annoying one
is correct.
黄色烦人的那个是对的。
Whoo!
哇!
We were once the High Guard.
我们曾经是最高卫队。
We witnessed
Sentinel's betrayal,
saw the Primes fall.
我们目睹了哨兵的背叛，擎天柱的陨落。
Since that day, we've been
fighting from the shadows,
从那天起，我们一直在暗地里战斗，
doing whatever we can
to sabotage Sentinel.
尽我们所能破坏哨兵。
That's great! We're--
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
太好了!我们——等等，等等。
Okay, okay.
We're good.
Everyone relax.
好吧,好吧。我们很好。每个人都放松。
I'm just saying we're allies.
我只是说我们是盟友。
We were on our way
back to Iacon,
我们在回艾肯的路上，
and now with your help,
we can unify Cybertron
against Sentinel Prime.
现在有了你的帮助，我们可以联合塞伯坦对抗哨兵擎天柱。
The idea of a unified
Cybertron is a myth.
统一的塞伯坦只是个神话。
All that counts is the strength
of one bot over another!
最重要的是一个机器人比另一个机器人强！
Okay. So, these guys
are a little intense.
好吧。所以，这些家伙有点紧张。
Yeah. Just a little.
是的。只会一点点。
Hey!
嘿!
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I tell you
what I'm not doing.
我告诉你我不会做什么。
I'm not cowering
in some busted ship,
playing king of the throne.
我才不要躲在破船里，扮演国王的角色。
I'm not pretending
like I'm making a difference
我没有假装我能改变什么
by throwing one punch
and then running away to hide!
打了一拳，然后跑开躲起来！
I found out
that Sentinel is rotten today,
我今天发现哨兵酒吧烂透了，
and I'm gonna
make him pay for it.
我要让他为此付出代价
Today!
今天!
You think you can insult me
and just walk away?
你以为你侮辱了我就能离开吗？
No one leaves here
unless I say so.
没有我的命令，谁也不许离开。
Is that right?
对吗？
Well, how can you say so
你怎么能这么说呢
with my head in your teeth?
把我的头塞进你的嘴里？
D!
D !
Whoa!
哇!
Hit me!
打我!
Do it! Come on! Yeah, more!
做到!来吧!是的,更多!
D-16! D-16! D-16!
D-16 !D-16 !D-16 !
You want to see the strength
of one bot over another? Huh?
你想看看一个机器人比另一个机器人强吗？嗯?
Is that
all you've got, tough bot?
这就是你的全部能耐吗，硬汉？
Let's go! Do it! Come on!
我们走吧!做到!来吧!
Please! I beg you!
拜托!我求你了！
Stop!
D, he's not the enemy!
停!D，他不是敌人！
Bear witness!
见证!
This is the last time
I show mercy!
这是我最后一次仁慈！
Decide right now:
现在就决定：
You can stay here in hiding,
bowing before
your pathetic leader,
你可以躲在这里，向你可怜的领导鞠躬，
or follow me
as we march on Iacon
或者跟随我向伊肯进军
and I take down Sentinel
once and for all!
我要彻底干掉哨兵！
D-16! D-16! D-16!
D-16 !D-16 !D-16 !
B, come on!
B，别这样！
Engage all hostiles!
I've got the bridge!
攻击所有敌人！我找到桥了！
Elita, get down!
艾丽塔，趴下！
I feel like someone
dropped a cliff on me.
我感觉就像有人把悬崖砸在我身上。
Where are the others?
其他人呢？
Sentinel's troops
took as many prisoners
as they could carry.
哨兵部队尽可能多地俘虏了他们的俘虏。
They got D-16 and B.
他们有D-16和B。
Oh, no.
哦,不。
And half of those
High-Guard nutjobs.
还有一半的高警备队疯子。
Our proof.
我们的证据。
It's gone.
这是一去不复返了。
So, what do we do now?
那么，我们现在该怎么办？
D was right.
D是对的。
About what?
Everything.
关于什么?一切。
Look at it. Look around.
This is a disaster.
看看它。环顾四周。这是一场灾难。
It's all my fault.
都是我的错。
I should have
stayed on protocol.
我应该按规定办事的。
Listen to me.
I really want you to hear this.
听我说。我真的想让你听听。
Are you listening?
你在听吗？
I'm better than you.
我比你强。
Yeah, okay,
I'm hearing you.
好吧，我听到了。
I'm better than you
in every way,
我各方面都比你强，
except you have hope.
除了你还有希望。
You always have. You went back
into the mine to rescue Jazz.
你一直都是。你回矿井去救爵士了。
You snuck up
to the surface to find
the Matrix of Leadership.
你潜到地表去找领导矩阵。
Yeah,
and how'd that work out?
是啊，那结果如何？
My point is,
我的观点是，
that your instincts tell you
to break protocol for a reason.
你的直觉告诉你打破常规是有原因的。
This blind optimism
that you have
你这种盲目的乐观
is why you make such bold
and courageous choices,
所以你才会做出如此大胆勇敢的选择，
that are also extremely stupid.
这也是非常愚蠢的。
First time
giving a pep talk?
第一次给人打气？
You're inspiring.
你是鼓舞人心的。
You can envision a better future
that no one else can see.
你可以设想一个别人看不到的更美好的未来。
And if we ever want to see
B and D-16 again,
如果我们还想再见到B和D-16，
that is the Orion Pax
that we need right now.
这就是我们现在需要的猎户座和平。
Listen to me.
听我说。
We can do this.
我们可以做到。
Those Energon trains
will be heading
back to Iacon.
那些能量列车会回艾肯的。
If we intercepted one--
如果我们拦截一个
Hell yes, I can reroute it.
What else do we need?
当然可以，我可以改道。我们还需要什么？
Well, my bold instincts tell me
we have to recruit some nutjobs.
我的直觉告诉我，我们得找些疯子。
I was afraid
you'd say that.
我就怕你会这么说。
Uh, Shockwave, Soundwave.
You in the back.
冲击波，声波。你在后面。
In order to save
our captured friends,
we have to act now.
为了救被俘的朋友，我们必须马上行动。
How about I blast you
back to Iacon?
我把你炸回艾康怎么样？
Oh! She punched me in my eye!
哦!她一拳打在我眼睛上！
Everyone, shut up!
All of you. Listen to him.
大家都闭嘴！你们所有人。听他说。
Most likely, our friends
are being held captive
很可能是我们的朋友被俘虏了
at the top
of Sentinel's tower.
在哨兵的塔顶
A surprise attack would
give us a chance to rescue them.
突然袭击会给我们一个营救他们的机会。
Impossible. We do not
have enough soldiers
or a way inside.
不可能的。我们没有足够的士兵，也没有办法进去。
Elita will get us in.
And I will get more troops.
伊莉塔会带我们进去的。我还会调集更多的军队。
Why should we follow you?
我们为什么要跟着你？
We will follow you.
我们会跟着你。
Attention, High Guard.
Prepare for battle.
注意，高卫。准备战斗。
What is our first move?
我们的第一步是什么？
We roll out.
我们推出。
What?
怎么啦？
Louder.
响亮。
Transform and roll out!
变换并推出！
I don't understand.
Why are we still alive?
我不明白。为什么我们还活着？
Look at this rowdy bunch!
The High Guard!
看看这群吵吵闹闹的人！高级守卫！
You know, you guys
have been tough to find.
知道吗，你们好难找啊。
Every trip to the surface,
I've been searching for you.
每次到地表，我都在寻找你。
Tracking the bots in the cave
led me right to them.
追踪洞穴里的机器人让我找到了他们。
Oh-ho-ho!
Oh-ho-ho !
You captured Starscream!
It was too easy.
你抓住了红蜘蛛！这太容易了。
I'm going to rip you apart
piece by piece
我要把你撕成碎片
so that your death
is painful!
所以你的死是痛苦的！
You'll regret
the day you were--
你会后悔的
You sound ridiculous.
It's weird.
你听起来很可笑。这很奇怪。
Oh, D-16,
what a tragic story you'll be.
D-16，你会是一个多么悲惨的故事。
Atop the leaderboard
in your sector
and secretly a traitor.
在你的领域名列前茅，暗地里却成了叛徒。
I'm not a traitor.
You're the traitor.
我不是叛徒。你是叛徒。
Nuh-uh. You, all of you,
are traitors.
Nuh-uh。你们，你们所有人，都是叛徒。
You've been working
with the Quintessons
to sabotage my expeditions.
你一直在和Quintessons合作破坏我的探险。
You're the reason
why I haven't found
the Matrix of Leadership yet.
你就是我还没找到领导力矩阵的原因。
None of that is true!
这些都不是真的！
Oh, trust me,
it'll be very true
相信我，这是真的
when I'm executing you
in front of all of Iacon.
当我在全体艾肯人面前处决你的时候
Because down here,
the truth is what I make it.
因为在这里，真相是我创造的。
Well, well.
What's this about?
嗯,很好。这是怎么回事？
I'm not kneeling
in front of you.
我不会跪在你面前。
Feeling confident, are we?
感觉很自信，是吗？
You don't scare me.
You want to know why?
你吓不倒我。你想知道为什么吗？
Please.
请。
Because I don't have
anything left to lose.
因为我已经没什么可失去的了。
You took it all.
你全拿走了。
I sure did.
当然了。
Ah, Megatronus Prime.
啊，威震天王。
Of course you were a fan.
Megatronus was
the coolest Prime!
你当然是粉丝了。威震天是最酷的擎天柱！
The biggest!
The baddest! The toughest!
最大的!最坏的!最艰难的!
That's why,
after I killed him,
所以我杀了他之后，
I took his cog for myself.
我把他的齿轮夺去了。
He was greater
than you'll ever be!
他比你伟大得多！
I don't know. I'm pretty great.
我不知道。我很好。
But I can understand why you'd
want to wear his face over mine.
但我能理解你为什么想用他的脸来代替我。
Here.
在这里。
Let's make sure
it doesn't come off.
我们要确保它不会脱落。
Okay.
好吧。
I can do this.
我能做到。
You can't be serious.
We just worked
22 shifts without a break!
你不是认真的吧。我们连续干了22个班！
These miners need rest
and time to repair and--
这些矿工需要休息和时间来修复和
Sentinel Prime
wants more Energon.
哨兵质点需要更多能量。
So get back in the mines
before I make you
get back in the--
所以在我让你回矿井之前赶紧回去
Who was that?
Did you see
who that was?
那是谁？你看到那是谁了吗？
That can't be him.
不可能是他。
Is that...
是……
It can't be.
这不可能。
Orion?
Jazz.
猎户星座吗?爵士乐。
Is it really you?
真的是你吗？
Yeah, I know I, uh,
look a little different.
是啊，我知道我看起来有点不一样了。
"Little"?
“小”?
There's nothing
"little" about you.
你一点都不“小”。
Uh, how is this possible?
这怎么可能？
Sentinel told us you died
from your race injuries.
哨兵告诉我们你死于种族伤害。
Sentinel is a liar.
哨兵是个骗子。
What?
Huh?
怎么啦？嗯?
Look, I know how this will sound
coming from me.
听着，我知道这听起来像是我说的。
I was never
the most focused miner.
我从来都不是最专注的矿工。
But as you can see,
everything is different now.
但正如你所见，现在一切都不同了。
I went to the surface
and I learned the truth.
我来到水面，了解了真相。
My friends,
我的朋友,
we were all born
with transformation cogs.
我们生来就有变形的齿轮。
And then Sentinel,
he stole them from us.
然后哨兵，他从我们这里偷走了它们。
He took away our ability
to make our own decisions.
他剥夺了我们自己做决定的能力。
He stole our freedom.
他偷走了我们的自由。
But now, I'm offering you
your first real choice.
但现在，我给你第一个真正的选择。
You can work a 23rd shift
and mine yourself to death
你可以上第23班，把自己挖死
or fight back
against Sentinel with me.
或者和我一起对抗哨兵
Right now.
现在。
How are we supposed to do that?
We can't fight.
We don't have cogs.
我们该怎么做呢？我们不能战斗。我们没有齿轮。
What defines a Transformer
is not the cog in its chest
定义变形金刚的不是它胸前的齿轮
but the spark
that resides in their core.
而是他们内心深处的火花。
A spark that gives you the will
to make your world better.
给你意志让你的世界变得更美好的火花。
And that spark,
Sentinel can never
take from us.
而那火花，哨兵永远无法从我们这里夺走。
There's not enough of us.
We'd need an army.
我们的人不够多。我们需要一支军队。
And we have one.
Elita is bringing troops.
我们有一个。伊莉塔正在带军队来。
We are not alone in this.
我们并不孤单。
If we want to be in control
of our own destiny,
如果我们想掌握自己的命运，
we will have to
fight for it.
我们必须为此而战。
Now is the time
for us to stand up...
现在是我们站起来的时候了……
...for ourselves.
…为我们自己。
Stand up for this injustice.
为这种不公正挺身而出。
I promise you
this fight will be worth it.
我向你保证这场战斗是值得的。
Follow me.
跟我来。
Nothing can stop us
when we stand together.
当我们站在一起时，没有什么能阻止我们。
Together as one.
合为一体。
Orion Pax! Orion Pax! Orion Pax!
猎户座罗马帝国!猎户座罗马帝国!猎户座罗马帝国!
Elita, it's time.
Elita，时间到了。
You got it.
你说对了。
Buckle up, Blinky.
We're going in.
系好安全带，Blinky。我们要进去了。
Not a good idea.
这不是个好主意。
D, stay down.
D，趴下。
Well, that's a shame.
哦，那太遗憾了。
You really were
a great miner.
你真是个了不起的矿工。
We've got a breach!
Protect Sentinel!
有人入侵了！保护哨兵!
They spotted us.
It's about to get bumpy.
他们发现了我们。要开始颠簸了。
High Guard, eject.
高卫，弹射。
Come on! Move out!
来吧!搬出去!
There's too many.
We have to abort!
太多了。我们必须中止行动！
We're not gonna make it.
我们撑不过去了。
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo-hoo !
Metal to the pedal, miners!
开足马力，矿工们！
Let's break some protocol!
让我们打破一些规则吧！
That's what
I'm talking about, Pax!
我说的就是这个，帕克斯！
Whoa! That's intense.
哇!这是强烈的。
You can't win, miner.
I see everything!
你赢不了的，矿工。我什么都看见了！
That's right, you do.
没错，你有。
Except the tower we're
about to crash into.
除了我们即将撞上的那座塔。
What's going on?
这是怎么呢？
Hey!
嘿!
What has he done to you?
他对你做了什么？
This is nothing compared to
what I'm gonna do to Sentinel.
这跟我要对哨兵做的事比起来根本不算什么。
Soundwave,
free the prisoners.
声波，释放囚犯。
I know how to stop him.
Airachnid is the answer.
我知道怎么阻止他。Airachnid就是答案。
I'm doing this my way.
D!
我要按我的方式来。D !
Yes!
是的!
Whoa!
哇!
Whoa-ho-ho!
Whoa-ho-ho !
I got a battle mask!
我有一个战斗面具！
Elita! Battle mask!
Elita !战斗面具!
It appeared
when this guy tried to--
当这个人试图
Knife hands?
I have knife hands!
刀手?我的手像刀一样！
What the--?
——什么?
Badassatron.
Badassatron。
Where's Sentinel?
哨兵在哪儿?
You pathetic little twits.
你们这些可怜的小笨蛋。
Did you really think
that you could knock down
everything I've built?
你真以为你能把我建造的一切都推倒吗？
It's over, Sentinel.
You can't escape the truth.
What truth?
结束了，哨兵。你无法逃避真相。什么真理?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
我从你刚出生的胸膛里取出了螺丝钉？
Forced you to mine
so that I could pay off
the Quintessons
逼你做我的，这样我就可以付钱给Quintessons了
and live like a king?
像国王一样生活？
None of that matters!
Because the truth...
这些都不重要！因为真相……
...is what I make it.
…是我做的。
Incoming!
传入的!
Whoa!
哇!
He's too strong.
I have a plan.
他太强壮了。我有个计划。
We need Airachnid.
Airachnid?
我们需要Airachnid。Airachnid吗?
We need her memory.
Where is she?
我们需要她的记忆。她在哪里？
Found her!
发现她!
Elita!
Elita !
Do not break her.
不要打断她。
Bring her
to the broadcast station.
带她去广播站。
We'll meet you there.
我们在那儿见。
Easier said than done.
说起来容易做起来难。
I said,
don't break her!
我说了，别伤害她！
Relax! I'm being very gentle.
放松点!我已经很温柔了。
Orion! Orion, look!
I have knife hands!
猎户!猎户座,看!我的手像刀一样！
I can see that.
我看得出来。
I'm gonna cut these guys.
Watch. Come here!
我要切掉这些家伙。手表。来这里!
You can jab them later.
We got to go.
你可以稍后再打。我们得走了。
Yeah!
是啊!
Uh, excuse me.
You can't be in here.
呃，打扰一下。你不能在这里。
B!
B !
These are not
the bad guys.
Why did you cut the door?
他们不是坏人。你为什么要剪门？
What? No, I didn't--
That was an-- I--
怎么啦？不，我没有，那是，我
It was already like that.
Right?
已经是那样了。对吧?
Yes, that's right.
That's right, yes.
是的，没错。没错，是的。
Yeah, it was already like--
Yes. Mm-hmm.
是的，就像。是的。嗯哼。
Attention, Iacon City.
注意，icon市。
Stand by for
a live transmission
from Sentinel Prime.
等待哨兵Prime的实时传输。
What's wrong, D-16?
怎么了，D-16？
Rise up!
起来!
That's why after I killed him--
这就是为什么在我杀了他之后——
That's why after I killed him,
I took his cog for myself.
这就是为什么我杀了他之后，我自己拿走了他的齿轮。
...cog for myself.
…
What truth?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
什么真理?我从你刚出生的胸膛里取出了螺丝钉？
Forced you to mine
so that I could pay off
强迫你做我的，这样我才能还清
the Quintessons
and live like a king?
《五堂课》然后活得像个国王？
What truth?
什么真理?
That I plucked the cogs
from your newborn chests?
我从你刚出生的胸膛里拔下了螺丝钉？
Forced you to mine
so that I could pay off
强迫你做我的，这样我才能还清
the Quintessons
and live like a king?
《五堂课》然后活得像个国王？
I'm working my miners
as hard as I can.
我正在尽我最大的努力让我的矿工们工作。
I swear I will
get you the rest!
我发誓我会把剩下的给你！
I'm working my miners
as hard as I can.
我正在尽我最大的努力让我的矿工们工作。
I swear I will
get you the rest!
我发誓我会把剩下的给你！
I'm working my miners
as hard as I can, I swear--
我已经尽我所能让我的矿工们工作了，我发誓——
Liar!
骗子!
We trusted you!
我们信任你！
Traitor!
叛徒!
Pax, we did it.
帕克斯，我们成功了。
D!
D !
D-16.
D-16。
We can lead Cybertron together!
我们可以一起领导塞伯坦！
Don't do this!
别这样！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
It's over, D.
结束了，D。
Everyone in Iacon
knows the truth.
艾肯的每个人都知道真相。
So do I!
我也是！
He took everything from us!
I have to do this!
他夺走了我们的一切！我必须这么做！
No, you don't.
不，你不需要。
Rebuilding Iacon
cannot begin
with an execution.
重建Iacon不能从处决开始。
He deserves to die!
Can't you see that?
他该死！你看不出来吗？
We're better than this.
Don't be like Sentinel.
我们能做得更好。不要像哨兵那样。
Pax,
罗马帝国,
you need to move
out of my way
before I move you myself.
在我动手之前，你得让开。
D, listen--
D,听——
Stop!
停!
No!
不!
No, no, no, no. Why?
不，不，不。为什么?
Why did you do that? Why?
你为什么要那样做？为什么?
D, no.
D,没有。
I'm done saving you.
我不想再救你了。
The Age of Primes has ended!
擎天柱时代结束了！
No more false prophets!
不要再有假先知！
Follow me and you will
never again be deceived.
跟着我，你就不会再受骗了。
Rise up!
起来!
Rise up! Rise up!
起来!起来!
Rise up!
起来!起来!起来!
Orion Pax,
猎户座帕克斯,
your noble sacrifice
for the greater good
你为更大的利益做出了崇高的牺牲
has proven you worthy
in the eyes of Primus.
已经在普里默斯的眼中证明了你的价值。
He entrusts in you
他信任你
the future of Cybertron
塞伯坦的未来
and the Matrix of Leadership!
以及《领导力矩阵》！
I will lead us all
into the future!
我将带领大家走向未来！
I...
我…
am...
Megatron!
威震天!
Arise...
出现…
Optimus Prime.
擎天柱。
Burn it down!
烧了它！
All of it!
全部！
All hail Megatron!
威震天万岁！
He's gonna kill everyone.
We have to stop him.
Come on.
他会杀了所有人。我们必须阻止他。来吧。
Stop! It's over.
停!这是结束了。
It's over when every last one
of his followers is dead!
当他的所有追随者都死了，一切就结束了！
Impossible.
不可能的。
Primus gave you the Matrix.
普里默斯给了你母体。
We could've built
the future together.
我们本可以一起创造未来。
I'll build it myself.
我自己来做。
After I tear down
everyone in my way!
等我把挡道的人都打倒了！
Ah!
啊!
We were given the power
to change our world
我们被赋予了改变世界的力量
and you chose to destroy it.
而你却选择了毁灭它。
Just like Sentinel.
就像哨兵一样。
You have betrayed Cybertron
and its citizens.
你背叛了塞伯坦和它的公民。
And you betrayed me.
你背叛了我。
Go.
走了。
Take the High Guard
and leave.
带上高卫队离开。
You are banished from Iacon.
你被驱逐出艾肯。
It didn't have to end
this way.
事情本不必这样结束的。
This isn't over, Prime.
这还没完，擎天柱。
High Guard, follow me!
高卫兵，跟我来！
The line
between friend and enemy
敌友分界
is not as clear
as I once believed.
不像我曾经认为的那样清晰。
Once it's crossed,
there's no going back.
一旦越过，就没有回头路了
Because some transformations
are permanent.
因为有些转换是永久的
Hey, Megatronus Prime.
Nice.
嘿，威震天王。好。
Oh, yeah.
Well, he's my hero.
哦,是的。他是我的英雄。
The greatest Prime
to ever live.
有史以来最伟大的擎天柱。
I'm D-16.
Orion Pax.
我D-16。猎户座Pax。
You ever mine Energon before?
你以前开采过能源吗？
No. You?
不。你吗?
No. I hear it's dangerous.
不。我听说这很危险。
Well, I'll tell you what.
好吧，我告诉你。
You watch my back,
I promise to watch yours.
你看着我，我保证也看着你。
All right.
好吧。
Thanks, Pax.
谢谢,Pax。
A new beginning
for Cybertron.
塞伯坦的新开始。
And a new leader.
还有一个新的领导人。
Yes, about that.
是的，关于那个。
I could use some help
from a bot who is
better than me in every way.
我可以从一个各方面都比我强的机器人那里得到一些帮助。
Who, me? Oh, no, no.
谁,我吗?哦，不，不。
I have a pretty sweet gig
working in waste management.
我在垃圾管理部门有份不错的工作。
Well, Captain,
I do owe you a promotion.
队长，我欠你一次升职。
How's Major Elita sound?
埃莉塔少校还好吗？
How about Commander?
指挥官呢？
Even better.
那就更好了。
And I'm sorry, B,
but I cannot let you
go back to sublevel 50.
我很抱歉，B，但我不能让你回到50层。
I may be a Prime now,
我现在可能是Prime会员了
but I'm gonna need you
by my side.
但我需要你在我身边
Are you serious?
This is the greatest
day of my life.
你是认真的吗？这是我一生中最棒的一天。
I get to work
for the government.
我为政府工作。
Okay. So that's new.
好吧。这是新的。
I'm sorry,
what is happening?
不好意思，发生什么事了？
And now we stand here
together as one...
现在我们站在一起作为一个人…
proving we all have
the power to transform,
证明我们都有改变的能力，
to become
who we were destined to be,
成为我们注定要成为的人，
to right wrongs,
to make our world better.
去纠正错误，让我们的世界更美好。
Because here,
freedom and autonomy
因为这里，自由和自治
are the rights
of all sentient beings.
是一切有情众生的权利。
Here,
all are truly Autobots.
在这里，所有人都是真正的汽车人。
This message is a warning
to all Quintessons.
此消息是对所有Quintessons的警告。
If you dare
return to Cybertron,
the Autobots will be waiting.
如果你敢回到塞伯坦，汽车人会等着你的。
I will be waiting.
我等你。
I am Optimus Prime.
我是擎天柱
Hey, guys! Great news,
the Energon's back!
嘿,伙计们!好消息，能量号回来了！
And I have a cog
and I can transform!
我有一个齿轮，我可以变形！
It's a long story.
I'll fill you in later.
说来话长。我以后再告诉你。
Oh! And here's the best part.
My hands are straight-up knives.
哦!这是最棒的部分。我的手是直刀。
Watch this. Knife hands!
看这个。刀手!
No!
不!
Sentinel the betrayer is dead.
哨兵：背叛者已死。
But his death has given life
to a new enemy.
但是他的死给了一个新的敌人生命。
A stronger enemy.
更强的敌人。
A personal enemy.
私人敌人。
We will not be blinded
by his deception.
我们不会被他的欺骗蒙蔽。
We are the ones who are...
我们是……
Decepticons!
霸天虎!
Rise up!
起来!
Rise up! Rise up!
起来!起来!